Tenma Rollins

github.com/tenmar linkedin.com/tenmarollins

+1 (206) 919-4143 • TenmaRollins@gmail.com

Native English Speaker Heritage Japanese Speaker

SUMMARY

Three years of experience leading both front-end and GCP-powered back-end development for both web and mobile applications, performing QA, bridging communication between departments, onboarding new team members, managing multi-platform development in a small team, and building full-featured prototypes to explore new technologies and resources.

LANGUAGES

- Javascript/Typescript
- Kotlin
- Swift
- Java
- C#
- Python
- SQL
- HTML + CSS + JSX

TECHNOLOGY

- React & React Native
- Redux
- Node.js
- Vue
- Google Cloud Platform
- Android Studio, XCode
- Visual Studio
- Git

SKILLS

- Communication
- Adaptability
- Quick Learner
- Time Management
- Leadership
- Teamwork
- Organized
- Problem Solving

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Handimaps — Seattle, WA

Lead Software Engineer (Full Time)

01/2019 - Present

- Trained and supported new hires to maintain and collaborate on native-mobile and web application development.
- Managed team for flagship project while utilizing concepts from Agile and TDD, and performed weekly code review and quality assurance.
- Architected and built full-featured prototypes to act as proof-of-concept presentations for new projects and to pitch to prospective clients with.

Associate Developer (Full Time)

06/2018 - 01/2019

- Acted as an Engineering Communication Bridge between all contacts: designers, front-end developers, management, clients.
- Frequently learned new technologies and tools in order to best adapt to changing specifications and project requirements.
- Developed client-controlled administration web portal for interfacing with our mobile applications and to produce real-time analytical data of app usage on-site

Intern Developer (Internship)

03/2018 - 06/2018

- Built front end prototype features and components for native Android (Java) and iOS (Swift) mobile applications.
- Built internal tools to assist aspects of the physical infrastructure setup, including streamlining setup of data translation into the backend.
- Improved performance and stability of Android and iOS mobile applications by resolving critical bugs both on the frontend and backend.

CoderDojo — Bellevue, WA

Tutor (Volunteer)

04/2017 - 06/2017

- Assisted in tutoring children in introductory programming projects using Python, HTML, and Scratch.
- Collaborated with a team of volunteers to strategically plan, develop, and implement more ambitious, exploratory projects and future lesson plans for prospective students.
- Developed interpersonal connections with a multitude of students at different skill levels to help facilitate their growth. Identified assistance opportunities and needs during lessons, answering questions/guiding students whenever necessary.

EDUCATION

University Of Washington

Bachelor of Computer Science and Systems Concentration in Database Design and Mobile Development Minor in Mathematics 09/2014-06/2018